var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "وَأَخَّرَ",
        "answer": "and kept back",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "wa-akhara",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " يُنَبَّأُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ بِمَا قَدَّمَ وَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَخَّرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to delay, to give respite",
        "waznTlit": "akhara",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْآخِرَةَ",
        "answer": "the Hereafter",
        "pcklId": "151",
        "rootWordId": 22,
        "tlit": "l-ākhirata",
        "frequency": "250",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَذَرُونَ الْآخِرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "أ خ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "آخِر",
        "waznEnglish": "Hereafter, end, last, later generations",
        "waznTlit": "ākhir",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "So when",
        "pcklId": "344",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا بَرِقَ الْبَصَرُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَإِذَا",
        "answer": "And when",
        "pcklId": "345",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "fa-idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا قَرَأْنَاهُ فَاتَّبِعْ قُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِذَا",
        "answer": "When",
        "pcklId": "346",
        "rootWordId": 27,
        "tlit": "idhā",
        "frequency": "409",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ التَّرَاقِيَ",
        "rootWord": "إِذَا",
        "rootWordType": "nominal",
        "wazn": "إِذَا",
        "waznEnglish": "when",
        "waznTlit": "idhā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Time adverb)"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "To",
        "pcklId": "717",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمُسْتَقَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "Towards",
        "pcklId": "718",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّهَا نَاظِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "To",
        "pcklId": "719",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمَسَاقُ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "إِلَىٰ",
        "answer": "to",
        "pcklId": "720",
        "rootWordId": 63,
        "tlit": "ilā",
        "frequency": "742",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ ذَهَبَ إِلَىٰ أَهْلِهِ يَتَمَطَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "إِلَىٰ",
        "rootWordType": "preposition",
        "wazn": "إِلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to, toward, until",
        "waznTlit": "ilā",
        "waznType": "Preposition"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَمَامَهُ",
        "answer": "(to) what is before him",
        "pcklId": "35",
        "rootWordId": 72,
        "tlit": "amāmahu",
        "frequency": "119",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ الْإِنْسَانُ لِيَفْجُرَ أَمَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ م م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَمَام",
        "waznEnglish": "in front of, before",
        "waznTlit": "amām",
        "waznType": "Time adverb"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "answer": "and the female",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 77,
        "tlit": "wal-unthā",
        "frequency": "30",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَ مِنْهُ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن ث",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أُنثَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "and the female",
        "waznTlit": "unthā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[the] man",
        "pcklId": "71",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَلَّنْ نَجْمَعَ عِظَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[the] man",
        "pcklId": "72",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ الْإِنْسَانُ لِيَفْجُرَ أَمَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[the] man",
        "pcklId": "73",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ أَيْنَ الْمَفَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[the] man",
        "pcklId": "74",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " يُنَبَّأُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ بِمَا قَدَّمَ وَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "[The] man",
        "pcklId": "75",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ الْإِنْسَانُ عَلَىٰ نَفْسِهِ بَصِيرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْإِنْسَانُ",
        "answer": "man",
        "pcklId": "76",
        "rootWordId": 78,
        "tlit": "l-insānu",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَنْ يُتْرَكَ سُدًى",
        "rootWord": "أ ن س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "إِنسَٰن",
        "waznEnglish": "you perceive",
        "waznTlit": "insān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَهْلِهِ",
        "answer": "his family",
        "pcklId": "121",
        "rootWordId": 82,
        "tlit": "ahlihi",
        "frequency": "127",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ ذَهَبَ إِلَىٰ أَهْلِهِ يَتَمَطَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "أ ه ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أ ه ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(the) People",
        "waznTlit": "hamza hā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَرِقَ",
        "answer": "is dazzled",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 117,
        "tlit": "bariqa",
        "frequency": "6",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا بَرِقَ الْبَصَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَرِقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be dazzled, to be frightened",
        "waznTlit": "bariqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَاسِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) distorted",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 122,
        "tlit": "bāsiratun",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ بَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب س ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَاسِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and scowled",
        "waznTlit": "bāsirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْبَصَرُ",
        "answer": "the vision",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "l-baṣaru",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "7",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا بَرِقَ الْبَصَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصَر",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَصِيرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) a witness",
        "pcklId": "138",
        "rootWordId": 129,
        "tlit": "baṣīratun",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ الْإِنْسَانُ عَلَىٰ نَفْسِهِ بَصِيرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ب ص ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَصِيرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "I perceived",
        "waznTlit": "baṣīrat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَلَغَتِ",
        "answer": "it reaches",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 157,
        "tlit": "balaghati",
        "frequency": "77",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ التَّرَاقِيَ",
        "rootWord": "ب ل غ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَلَغَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to reach",
        "waznTlit": "balagha",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَنَانَهُ",
        "answer": "his fingertips",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 159,
        "tlit": "banānahu",
        "frequency": "2",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلَىٰ قَادِرِينَ عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُسَوِّيَ بَنَانَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ب ن ن",
        "waznEnglish": "fingertip[s]",
        "waznTlit": "bā nūn nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بَيَانَهُ",
        "answer": "(is) its explanation",
        "pcklId": "57",
        "rootWordId": 173,
        "tlit": "bayānahu",
        "frequency": "523",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "19",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا بَيَانَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ب ي ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "بَيَان",
        "waznEnglish": "to make clear",
        "waznTlit": "bayān",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاتَّبِعْ",
        "answer": "then follow",
        "pcklId": "159",
        "rootWordId": 176,
        "tlit": "fa-ittabiʿ",
        "frequency": "172",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا قَرَأْنَاهُ فَاتَّبِعْ قُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ت ب ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱتَّبَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to follow",
        "waznTlit": "ittabaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "التَّرَاقِيَ",
        "answer": "the collar bones",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 181,
        "tlit": "l-tarāqiya",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "26",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا إِذَا بَلَغَتِ التَّرَاقِيَ",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ت ر ق",
        "waznEnglish": "the collar bones",
        "waznTlit": "tā rā qāf",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form VI)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُتْرَكَ",
        "answer": "he will be left",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 182,
        "tlit": "yut'raka",
        "frequency": "43",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَنْ يُتْرَكَ سُدًى",
        "rootWord": "ت ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَرَكَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave",
        "waznTlit": "taraka",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلَ",
        "answer": "Then made",
        "pcklId": "326",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿala",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَ مِنْهُ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَجْمَعَ",
        "answer": "We will assemble",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "najmaʿa",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَلَّنْ نَجْمَعَ عِظَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to collect",
        "waznTlit": "jamaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَجُمِعَ",
        "answer": "And are joined",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "wajumiʿa",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجُمِعَ الشَّمْسُ وَالْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمَعَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to gather, to collect",
        "waznTlit": "jamaʿa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "جَمْعَهُ",
        "answer": "(is) its collection",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 260,
        "tlit": "jamʿahu",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا جَمْعَهُ وَقُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ج م ع",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَمْع",
        "waznEnglish": "We will gather them",
        "waznTlit": "jamʿ",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُحِبُّونَ",
        "answer": "you love",
        "pcklId": "62",
        "rootWordId": 284,
        "tlit": "tuḥibbūna",
        "frequency": "95",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ تُحِبُّونَ الْعَاجِلَةَ",
        "rootWord": "ح ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْبَبْ",
        "waznEnglish": "to love, to like",
        "waznTlit": "aḥbab",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تُحَرِّكْ",
        "answer": "move",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 311,
        "tlit": "tuḥarrik",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُحَرِّكْ بِهِ لِسَانَكَ لِتَعْجَلَ بِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ح ر ك",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ح ر ك",
        "waznEnglish": "to move",
        "waznTlit": "ḥā rā kāf",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَيَحْسَبُ",
        "answer": "Does think",
        "pcklId": "38",
        "rootWordId": 316,
        "tlit": "ayaḥsabu",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَلَّنْ نَجْمَعَ عِظَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ح س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَسِبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think",
        "waznTlit": "ḥasiba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَيَحْسَبُ",
        "answer": "Does think",
        "pcklId": "39",
        "rootWordId": 316,
        "tlit": "ayaḥsabu",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَنْ يُتْرَكَ سُدًى",
        "rootWord": "ح س ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حَسِبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think",
        "waznTlit": "ḥasiba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُحْيِيَ",
        "answer": "give life",
        "pcklId": "61",
        "rootWordId": 381,
        "tlit": "yuḥ'yiya",
        "frequency": "184",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَيْسَ ذَٰلِكَ بِقَادِرٍ عَلَىٰ أَنْ يُحْيِيَ الْمَوْتَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ح ي ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَحْيَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to give life",
        "waznTlit": "aḥyā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَخَسَفَ",
        "answer": "And becomes dark",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 407,
        "tlit": "wakhasafa",
        "frequency": "8",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَخَسَفَ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "خ س ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خ س ف",
        "waznEnglish": "to cause to swallow",
        "waznTlit": "khā sīn fā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَخَلَقَ",
        "answer": "then He created",
        "pcklId": "165",
        "rootWordId": 431,
        "tlit": "fakhalaqa",
        "frequency": "261",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ كَانَ عَلَقَةً فَخَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "خ ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "خَلَقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to create",
        "waznTlit": "khalaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الذَّكَرَ",
        "answer": "(the) male",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 511,
        "tlit": "l-dhakara",
        "frequency": "292",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَ مِنْهُ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ك ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَكَر",
        "waznEnglish": "Remember",
        "waznTlit": "dhakar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "ذَهَبَ",
        "answer": "he went",
        "pcklId": "32",
        "rootWordId": 516,
        "tlit": "dhahaba",
        "frequency": "56",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ ذَهَبَ إِلَىٰ أَهْلِهِ يَتَمَطَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ذ ه ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ذَهَبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to go, to take away",
        "waznTlit": "dhahaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "919",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمُسْتَقَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّهَا",
        "answer": "their Lord",
        "pcklId": "920",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbihā",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّهَا نَاظِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبِّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "921",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbika",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمَسَاقُ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَاقٍ",
        "answer": "(will) cure",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 579,
        "tlit": "rāqin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقِيلَ مَنْ رَاقٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "you ascend",
        "waznTlit": "rāq",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُرِيدُ",
        "answer": "Desires",
        "pcklId": "144",
        "rootWordId": 600,
        "tlit": "yurīdu",
        "frequency": "148",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ الْإِنْسَانُ لِيَفْجُرَ أَمَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ر و د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرَادَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to intend, to desire, to want, to wish",
        "waznTlit": "arāda",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الزَّوْجَيْنِ",
        "answer": "two kinds",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 638,
        "tlit": "l-zawjayni",
        "frequency": "81",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "39",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَ مِنْهُ الزَّوْجَيْنِ الذَّكَرَ وَالْأُنْثَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ز و ج",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "زَوْج",
        "waznEnglish": "We married her to you",
        "waznTlit": "zawj",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَسْأَلُ",
        "answer": "He asks",
        "pcklId": "102",
        "rootWordId": 647,
        "tlit": "yasalu",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُ أَيَّانَ يَوْمُ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "س أ ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَأَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to ask",
        "waznTlit": "sa-ala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سُدًى",
        "answer": "neglected",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 674,
        "tlit": "sudan",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "36",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَنْ يُتْرَكَ سُدًى",
        "rootWord": "س د ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "س د ي",
        "waznEnglish": "neglected",
        "waznTlit": "sīn dāl yā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "السَّاقُ",
        "answer": "the leg",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 744,
        "tlit": "l-sāqu",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْتَفَّتِ السَّاقُ",
        "rootWord": "س و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "We drive them",
        "waznTlit": "sāq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالسَّاقِ",
        "answer": "about the leg",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 744,
        "tlit": "bil-sāqi",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " بِالسَّاقِ",
        "rootWord": "س و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "We drive them",
        "waznTlit": "sāq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَسَاقُ",
        "answer": "(will be) the driving",
        "pcklId": "15",
        "rootWordId": 744,
        "tlit": "l-masāqu",
        "frequency": "17",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "30",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمَسَاقُ",
        "rootWord": "س و ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَسَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "We drive them",
        "waznTlit": "masāq",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُسَوِّيَ",
        "answer": "We can restore",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "nusawwiya",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلَىٰ قَادِرِينَ عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُسَوِّيَ بَنَانَهُ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and proportioned",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 747,
        "tlit": "fasawwā",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ كَانَ عَلَقَةً فَخَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "س و ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سَوَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to fashion, to proportion",
        "waznTlit": "sawwā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الشَّمْسُ",
        "answer": "the sun",
        "pcklId": "29",
        "rootWordId": 797,
        "tlit": "l-shamsu",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجُمِعَ الشَّمْسُ وَالْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ش م س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ش م س",
        "waznEnglish": "the sun",
        "waznTlit": "shīn mīm sīn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَدَّقَ",
        "answer": "he accepted (the) truth",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 830,
        "tlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "frequency": "155",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا صَدَّقَ وَلَا صَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص د ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَدَّقَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to accept truth, to admit, to confirm, to believe",
        "waznTlit": "ṣaddaqa",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "صَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "he prayed",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 857,
        "tlit": "ṣallā",
        "frequency": "99",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "31",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَلَا صَدَّقَ وَلَا صَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ص ل و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "صَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to pray, to bless",
        "waznTlit": "ṣallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَظُنُّ",
        "answer": "Thinking",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "taẓunnu",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَظُنُّ أَنْ يُفْعَلَ بِهَا فَاقِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think, to assume, to guess",
        "waznTlit": "ẓanna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَظَنَّ",
        "answer": "And he is certain",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 944,
        "tlit": "waẓanna",
        "frequency": "69",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظَنَّ أَنَّهُ الْفِرَاقُ",
        "rootWord": "ظ ن ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ظَنَّ",
        "waznEnglish": "to think, to assume, to guess",
        "waznTlit": "ẓanna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِتَعْجَلَ",
        "answer": "to hasten",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 962,
        "tlit": "litaʿjala",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُحَرِّكْ بِهِ لِسَانَكَ لِتَعْجَلَ بِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَجِلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to hasten",
        "waznTlit": "ʿajila",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْعَاجِلَةَ",
        "answer": "the immediate",
        "pcklId": "44",
        "rootWordId": 962,
        "tlit": "l-ʿājilata",
        "frequency": "47",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "20",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا بَلْ تُحِبُّونَ الْعَاجِلَةَ",
        "rootWord": "ع ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَاجِلَةٌ",
        "waznEnglish": "Were you impatient",
        "waznTlit": "ʿājilatun",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَعَاذِيرَهُ",
        "answer": "his excuses",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 969,
        "tlit": "maʿādhīrahu",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ أَلْقَىٰ مَعَاذِيرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَعَاذِير",
        "waznEnglish": "make excuse",
        "waznTlit": "maʿādhīr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "عِظَامَهُ",
        "answer": "his bones",
        "pcklId": "126",
        "rootWordId": 1005,
        "tlit": "ʿiẓāmahu",
        "frequency": "128",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَيَحْسَبُ الْإِنْسَانُ أَلَّنْ نَجْمَعَ عِظَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ع ظ م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَظِيم",
        "waznEnglish": "honors",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaẓīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "عَلَقَةً",
        "answer": "a clinging substance",
        "pcklId": "5",
        "rootWordId": 1015,
        "tlit": "ʿalaqatan",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ كَانَ عَلَقَةً فَخَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ع ل ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَلَقَة",
        "waznEnglish": "a clinging substance",
        "waznTlit": "ʿalaqat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِيَفْجُرَ",
        "answer": "to give (the) lie",
        "pcklId": "1",
        "rootWordId": 1108,
        "tlit": "liyafjura",
        "frequency": "24",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلْ يُرِيدُ الْإِنْسَانُ لِيَفْجُرَ أَمَامَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ف ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يَفْجُرَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to give lie",
        "waznTlit": "yafjura",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَفَرُّ",
        "answer": "(is) the escape",
        "pcklId": "10",
        "rootWordId": 1118,
        "tlit": "l-mafaru",
        "frequency": "11",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ أَيْنَ الْمَفَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَفَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "So I fled",
        "waznTlit": "mafarr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفِرَاقُ",
        "answer": "(is) the parting",
        "pcklId": "69",
        "rootWordId": 1124,
        "tlit": "l-firāqu",
        "frequency": "72",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "28",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَظَنَّ أَنَّهُ الْفِرَاقُ",
        "rootWord": "ف ر ق",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فِرَاق",
        "waznEnglish": "We parted",
        "waznTlit": "firāq",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form III)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُفْعَلَ",
        "answer": "will be done",
        "pcklId": "81",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "yuf'ʿala",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " تَظُنُّ أَنْ يُفْعَلَ بِهَا فَاقِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَاقِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "backbreaking",
        "pcklId": "13",
        "rootWordId": 1145,
        "tlit": "fāqiratun",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "25",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " تَظُنُّ أَنْ يُفْعَلَ بِهَا فَاقِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ف ق ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَاقِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "[the] poverty",
        "waznTlit": "fāqirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَادِرِينَ",
        "answer": "(We are) Able",
        "pcklId": "118",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "qādirīna",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلَىٰ قَادِرِينَ عَلَىٰ أَنْ نُسَوِّيَ بَنَانَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَادِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qādir",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِقَادِرٍ",
        "answer": "(He) Able",
        "pcklId": "119",
        "rootWordId": 1181,
        "tlit": "biqādirin",
        "frequency": "132",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَيْسَ ذَٰلِكَ بِقَادِرٍ عَلَىٰ أَنْ يُحْيِيَ الْمَوْتَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ق د ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَادِر",
        "waznEnglish": "they have control",
        "waznTlit": "qādir",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَدَّمَ",
        "answer": "he sent forth",
        "pcklId": "25",
        "rootWordId": 1183,
        "tlit": "qaddama",
        "frequency": "48",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " يُنَبَّأُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ بِمَا قَدَّمَ وَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ق د م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَدَّمَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send forth, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "qaddama",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قَرَأْنَاهُ",
        "answer": "We have recited it",
        "pcklId": "12",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "qaranāhu",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا قَرَأْنَاهُ فَاتَّبِعْ قُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَرَأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to read, to recite",
        "waznTlit": "qara-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقُرْآنَهُ",
        "answer": "and its recitation",
        "pcklId": "86",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "waqur'ānahu",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "17",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِنَّ عَلَيْنَا جَمْعَهُ وَقُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "قُرْآنَهُ",
        "answer": "its recitation",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 1186,
        "tlit": "qur'ānahu",
        "frequency": "88",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "18",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَإِذَا قَرَأْنَاهُ فَاتَّبِعْ قُرْآنَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قُرْءَان",
        "waznEnglish": "is recited",
        "waznTlit": "qur'ān",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمُسْتَقَرُّ",
        "answer": "(is) the place of rest",
        "pcklId": "37",
        "rootWordId": 1190,
        "tlit": "l-mus'taqaru",
        "frequency": "38",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "12",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّكَ يَوْمَئِذٍ الْمُسْتَقَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "ق ر ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مُسْتَقَرّ",
        "waznEnglish": "and cool",
        "waznTlit": "mus'taqarr",
        "waznType": "Passive participle (form X)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُقْسِمُ",
        "answer": "I swear",
        "pcklId": "18",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "uq'simu",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا أُقْسِمُ بِيَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْسَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to swear",
        "waznTlit": "aqsamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أُقْسِمُ",
        "answer": "I swear",
        "pcklId": "19",
        "rootWordId": 1201,
        "tlit": "uq'simu",
        "frequency": "33",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِالنَّفْسِ اللَّوَّامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق س م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَقْسَمُ",
        "waznEnglish": "to swear",
        "waznTlit": "aqsamu",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقَمَرُ",
        "answer": "the moon",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1229,
        "tlit": "l-qamaru",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "8",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَخَسَفَ الْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق م ر",
        "waznEnglish": "the moon",
        "waznTlit": "qāf mīm rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْقَمَرُ",
        "answer": "and the moon",
        "pcklId": "24",
        "rootWordId": 1229,
        "tlit": "wal-qamaru",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "9",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَجُمِعَ الشَّمْسُ وَالْقَمَرُ",
        "rootWord": "ق م ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ق م ر",
        "waznEnglish": "the moon",
        "waznTlit": "qāf mīm rā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَقُولُ",
        "answer": "Will say",
        "pcklId": "1596",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "yaqūlu",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "10",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يَقُولُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ أَيْنَ الْمَفَرُّ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَقِيلَ",
        "answer": "And it is said",
        "pcklId": "1597",
        "rootWordId": 1245,
        "tlit": "waqīla",
        "frequency": "1722",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "27",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَقِيلَ مَنْ رَاقٍ",
        "rootWord": "ق و ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قَالَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to say",
        "waznTlit": "qāla",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Resurrection",
        "pcklId": "556",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "l-qiyāmati",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا أُقْسِمُ بِيَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِيَٰمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qiyāmat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "answer": "(of) the Resurrection",
        "pcklId": "557",
        "rootWordId": 1246,
        "tlit": "l-qiyāmati",
        "frequency": "660",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُ أَيَّانَ يَوْمُ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ق و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "قِيَٰمَة",
        "waznEnglish": "they stand (still)",
        "waznTlit": "qiyāmat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَذَّبَ",
        "answer": "he denied",
        "pcklId": "171",
        "rootWordId": 1263,
        "tlit": "kadhaba",
        "frequency": "282",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَٰكِنْ كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك ذ ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَذَّبَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to deny, to reject",
        "waznTlit": "kadhaba",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَكُ",
        "answer": "he",
        "pcklId": "1325",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "yaku",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَكُ نُطْفَةً مِنْ مَنِيٍّ يُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَانَ",
        "answer": "he was",
        "pcklId": "1326",
        "rootWordId": 1305,
        "tlit": "kāna",
        "frequency": "1390",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "38",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ كَانَ عَلَقَةً فَخَلَقَ فَسَوَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ك و ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَانَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to be",
        "waznTlit": "kāna",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "لِسَانَكَ",
        "answer": "your tongue",
        "pcklId": "23",
        "rootWordId": 1330,
        "tlit": "lisānaka",
        "frequency": "25",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "16",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا تُحَرِّكْ بِهِ لِسَانَكَ لِتَعْجَلَ بِهِ",
        "rootWord": "ل س ن",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل س ن",
        "waznEnglish": "their tongues",
        "waznTlit": "lām sīn nūn",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَالْتَفَّتِ",
        "answer": "And is wound",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1340,
        "tlit": "wal-tafati",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "29",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَالْتَفَّتِ السَّاقُ بِالسَّاقِ",
        "rootWord": "ل ف ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ٱلْتَفَّتِ",
        "waznEnglish": "to wind",
        "waznTlit": "al'taffati",
        "waznType": "Verb (form VIII)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلْقَىٰ",
        "answer": "he presents",
        "pcklId": "92",
        "rootWordId": 1347,
        "tlit": "alqā",
        "frequency": "146",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "15",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَوْ أَلْقَىٰ مَعَاذِيرَهُ",
        "rootWord": "ل ق ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَلْقَىٰٓ",
        "waznEnglish": "to cast, to throw, to meet, to offer",
        "waznTlit": "alqā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "اللَّوَّامَةِ",
        "answer": "self-accusing",
        "pcklId": "4",
        "rootWordId": 1359,
        "tlit": "l-lawāmati",
        "frequency": "14",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِالنَّفْسِ اللَّوَّامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ل و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "لَّوَّامَة",
        "waznEnglish": "you blamed me",
        "waznTlit": "lawwāmat",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَلَيْسَ",
        "answer": "Is not",
        "pcklId": "85",
        "rootWordId": 1363,
        "tlit": "alaysa",
        "frequency": "89",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَيْسَ ذَٰلِكَ بِقَادِرٍ عَلَىٰ أَنْ يُحْيِيَ الْمَوْتَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ل ي س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ل ي س",
        "waznEnglish": "to not be",
        "waznTlit": "lām yā sīn",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَتَمَطَّىٰ",
        "answer": "swaggering",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1403,
        "tlit": "yatamaṭṭā",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "33",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ ذَهَبَ إِلَىٰ أَهْلِهِ يَتَمَطَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ط و",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "م ط و",
        "waznEnglish": "to swagger",
        "waznTlit": "mīm ṭā wāw",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُمْنَىٰ",
        "answer": "emitted",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1420,
        "tlit": "yum'nā",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَكُ نُطْفَةً مِنْ مَنِيٍّ يُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "يُمْنَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to emit",
        "waznTlit": "yum'nā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَنِيٍّ",
        "answer": "semen",
        "pcklId": "20",
        "rootWordId": 1420,
        "tlit": "maniyyin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَكُ نُطْفَةً مِنْ مَنِيٍّ يُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م ن ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّنِىّ",
        "waznEnglish": "he recited",
        "waznTlit": "maniīī",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْمَوْتَىٰ",
        "answer": "(to) the dead",
        "pcklId": "148",
        "rootWordId": 1424,
        "tlit": "l-mawtā",
        "frequency": "165",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "40",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَيْسَ ذَٰلِكَ بِقَادِرٍ عَلَىٰ أَنْ يُحْيِيَ الْمَوْتَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "م و ت",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّيِّت",
        "waznEnglish": "(should) you die",
        "waznTlit": "mayyit",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يُنَبَّأُ",
        "answer": "Will be informed",
        "pcklId": "45",
        "rootWordId": 1434,
        "tlit": "yunabba-u",
        "frequency": "160",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "13",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " يُنَبَّأُ الْإِنْسَانُ يَوْمَئِذٍ بِمَا قَدَّمَ وَأَخَّرَ",
        "rootWord": "ن ب أ",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَبَّأَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to inform",
        "waznTlit": "nabba-a",
        "waznType": "Verb (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَاضِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "(will be) radiant",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 1483,
        "tlit": "nāḍiratun",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ نَاضِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ض ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَّاضِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "radiance",
        "waznTlit": "nāḍirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "نُطْفَةً",
        "answer": "a semen-drop",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 1485,
        "tlit": "nuṭ'fatan",
        "frequency": "12",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "37",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَكُ نُطْفَةً مِنْ مَنِيٍّ يُمْنَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "ن ط ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ن ط ف",
        "waznEnglish": "a minute quantity of semen",
        "waznTlit": "nūn ṭā fā",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَاظِرَةٌ",
        "answer": "looking",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 1487,
        "tlit": "nāẓiratun",
        "frequency": "129",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "23",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " إِلَىٰ رَبِّهَا نَاظِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ظ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَاظِرَة",
        "waznEnglish": "(were) looking",
        "waznTlit": "nāẓirat",
        "waznType": "Active participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِالنَّفْسِ",
        "answer": "by the soul",
        "pcklId": "286",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "bil-nafsi",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَا أُقْسِمُ بِالنَّفْسِ اللَّوَّامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "نَفْسِهِ",
        "answer": "himself",
        "pcklId": "287",
        "rootWordId": 1500,
        "tlit": "nafsihi",
        "frequency": "298",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "14",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " بَلِ الْإِنْسَانُ عَلَىٰ نَفْسِهِ بَصِيرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "ن ف س",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "نَفْس",
        "waznEnglish": "self, soul, person, mind",
        "waznTlit": "nafs",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وُجُوهٌ",
        "answer": "Faces",
        "pcklId": "65",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wujūhun",
        "frequency": "78",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "22",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ نَاضِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَوُجُوهٌ",
        "answer": "And faces",
        "pcklId": "66",
        "rootWordId": 1592,
        "tlit": "wawujūhun",
        "frequency": "78",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "24",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَوُجُوهٌ يَوْمَئِذٍ بَاسِرَةٌ",
        "rootWord": "و ج ه",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَجْه",
        "waznEnglish": "[I] have turned",
        "waznTlit": "wajh",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَذَرُونَ",
        "answer": "And leave",
        "pcklId": "43",
        "rootWordId": 1600,
        "tlit": "watadharūna",
        "frequency": "45",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "21",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَتَذَرُونَ الْآخِرَةَ",
        "rootWord": "و ذ ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "و ذ ر",
        "waznEnglish": "to leave, to forsake",
        "waznTlit": "wāw dhāl rā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَزَرَ",
        "answer": "refuge",
        "pcklId": "7",
        "rootWordId": 1605,
        "tlit": "wazara",
        "frequency": "27",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "11",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " كَلَّا لَا وَزَرَ",
        "rootWord": "و ز ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "وَزَر",
        "waznEnglish": "they bear",
        "waznTlit": "wazar",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "answer": "and turned away",
        "pcklId": "104",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "watawallā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "32",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَلَٰكِنْ كَذَّبَ وَتَوَلَّىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَوَلَّىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "to turn",
        "waznTlit": "tawallā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form V)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "Woe",
        "pcklId": "114",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "awlā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " أَوْلَىٰ لَكَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "awlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَوْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "and woe",
        "pcklId": "115",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "fa-awlā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "34",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَوْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "awlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "woe",
        "pcklId": "116",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "awlā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " ثُمَّ أَوْلَىٰ لَكَ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "awlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَأَوْلَىٰ",
        "answer": "and woe",
        "pcklId": "117",
        "rootWordId": 1648,
        "tlit": "fa-awlā",
        "frequency": "232",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "35",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " فَأَوْلَىٰ",
        "rootWord": "و ل ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَوْلَىٰ",
        "waznEnglish": "(are) close to you",
        "waznTlit": "awlā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِيَوْمِ",
        "answer": "by (the) Day",
        "pcklId": "304",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "biyawmi",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " لَا أُقْسِمُ بِيَوْمِ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَوْمُ",
        "answer": "(is the) Day",
        "pcklId": "305",
        "rootWordId": 1664,
        "tlit": "yawmu",
        "frequency": "405",
        "surahnum": "75",
        "ayahnum": "6",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " يَسْأَلُ أَيَّانَ يَوْمُ الْقِيَامَةِ",
        "rootWord": "ي و م",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ي و م",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Day",
        "waznTlit": "yā wāw mīm",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Noun)"
    }
]; 
export default words;